------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
COMP4300 - 2023 - Assignment 3
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Assignment Notes:
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
blank
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Program Specification:
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

This game must have the following features:

Assets:
- Entities in the game will be rendered using various Textures and Animations
  which we will be calling Assets (along with fonts)
- Assets are loaded once at the beginning of the program and stored in the
  Assets class, which is stored by the GameEngine class
- All Assets are defined in assets.txt, with the syntax defines below

Note:
- All entity positions denote the center of their rectangular sprite
  It also denotes the center of the bounding box, if it has one
  This is set via sprite.setOrigin() in the Animation class constructor

Player:
- *The player Entity in the game is represented by Megaman, which has serveral
  different Animations: Stand, Run, and Air. You must determin which state
  the playeris currently in and assign the correct Animation.
- *The player moves with the following controls:
  Left: A key, Right: D key, Jump: W key, Shoot: Space Key
- *The player can move left, move right, or shoot at any time during the game
  This means the player can move left/right while in the air
- *The player can only jump if it is currently standing on a tile
- *If the jump key is held, the player should not continuously jump, but
  instead it should only jump once per button press. If the player lets 
  go of the jump key mid-jump, it should start falling back down immediately
- *If the player moves left/right, the player's sprite will face in that 
  direction until the other direction has been pressed
- Bullets shot by the player travel in the direction the player is facing
- *The player collides with 'Tile' entities in the level (see level syntax) and
  cannot move through them. The player land on a Tile entity and stand in place
  if it falls on it from above
- *The player does not collide with 'Dec' (decoration) entities in the level
- *The player should have a Gravity component which constantly accelerates it
  downward on the screen until it collides with a tile
- *The player has a maximum speed specified in the level file (see below) which
  it should not exceed in either x or y direction
- *The player will be given a CBoundingBox of a specified in the level file
- *The player's sprite  and bounding box are centered on the player's position

Animations:
- See below for Animation asset specification
- *Animations are implemented by storing multiple frames inside a texture
- *The Animation class handles frame advancement based on animation speed
- *You need to implement Animation::update() to properly progress animations
- You need to implement Animation::hasEnded() which returns true if an
  animation has finished its last frame, false or otherwise
- *Animations can be repeating (loop forever) or non-repeating (play once)
- Any entity with a non-repeating animation should be destroyed once its
  Animation's hasEnded() returns true (has finished one cycle)

Decoration Entities:
- *Decoration entities ('Dec' in a level file) are simply drawn to the screen,
  and do not interact with any other entities in the game in any way
- *Decorations can be given any Animation in the game, but intuitively they
  should be reserved for things like clouds, buses, etc

Tiles:
- *Tiles are Entities that define the level geometry and interact with players
- *Tiles can be given any Animation that is defined in the Asset file
- *Tiles will be given a CBoundingBox equal to the size of the animation
  tile->getComponent<CAnimation>().animation.getSize()
- *The current animation displayed for a tile can be retreived with:
   tile->getComponent<CAnimation>().animation.getName()
- *Tiles have different behavior depending on which Animation they are given

  Brick Tiles:
  - *Brick tiles are given the 'Brick' Animation
  - When a brick tile collides with a bullet, or is hit by a player from below:
    - * Its animation should change to 'Explosion' (non-repeat)
    - Non-repeating animation entities are destroyed when hasEnded() is true
    - * Its CBoundingBox componenet should be removed

  Question Tiles:
  - *Question tiles are given the 'Question' Animation when created
  - *When a Question tile is hit by a player from below, 2 things happen:
    - *Its Animation changes to the darker 'Question2' animation
    - *A temporary lifespan entity with the 'Coin' animation should appear
      for 30 frames, 64 pixels above the location of the Question entity

Drawing:
- *Entity rendering has been implemented for you, no need to change that system

Bonus:
- Any special effect which do not alter game play can be added for up to
  5% bonus marks on the assignment. Note that assignments cannot go above
  100% total marks, but the 5% bonus can overwrite any marks lost in other
  areas of the assignment
- You also develop a 'special weapon' that has special effect which can
  also contribute to the 5% bonus marks available on the assignment.
- I will show off some of the more impressive bonus submissions in class

Misc:
- *The 'P' key should pause the game
- *Pressing the 'T' key toggles drawing textures
- *Pressing the 'C' key toggels drawing bounding boxes of entities
- *Pressing the 'G' key toggles drawing of the grid
  This should be very helpful for debugging
- *The 'ESC' key should go 'back' to the Main Menu, or quit if on the Main Menu

-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Level Creation
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------

For this assignemnt you are also required to create your own level. This level
should include some interesting gameplay. Include this level in the zip file as
level.txt, and I will show off some of the more intersting levels in class
after the assignment is due.

------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Config Files
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------



------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Assets File Specification
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

There will be three different line types in the Assets file, each of which
corresponds to a different type of Asset. They are as follows:

Texture Asset Specification:
Texture N P
  Texture Name     N		std::string (it will have no spaces)
  Texture FilePath P		std::string (it will have no spaces)

Animation Asset Specification:
Animation N T F S
  Animation Name   N		std::string (it will have no spaces)
  Texture Name     T		std::string (refers to an existing texture)
  Frame Count      F		int (number of frames in the Animation)
  Anim Speed       S		int (number of game frames between anim frames)

For Asset Specification:
Font N P
  Font Name		   N		std::string (it will have no spaces)
  Font File Path   P		std::string (it will have no spaces)

----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Level Specification File
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Game levels will be specified by a level file, which will contain a list of
entity specifications, one per line. It will also contain a single line which
specifies properties of the player in that level. In this way, you can define
an entire level in the data file, rather than in programming code. The sytax
of the lines of the Level file are as follows.

IMPORTANT NOTE:
  All (GX, GY) positions given in the level specification file are given in
  'grid' coordinates. The 'grid' cells are of size 64 by 64 pixels, and the
  entity should be positioned such that the bottom left corner of its texture
  is aligned with the bottom left corner of the given grid coordinate. The 
  grid starts at (0,0) in the bottom-left of the screen, and can be seen by
  pressing the 'G' key while the game is running.

Tile Entity Specification:
Tile N GX GY
  Animation Name     N     std::string (Animation asset name for this tile)
  GX Grid X Pos      GX    float
  GY Grid Y Pos      GY    float

Decoration Entity Specification:
Dec N X Y
  Animation Name     N     std::string (Animation asset name for this file)
  X Position         X     float
  Y Position         Y     float

Player Specification
Player GX GY CW CH SX SY SM GY B
  GX, GY Grid Pos    X, Y   float, float
  BoundingBox W/H    CW, CH float, float
  Left/Right Speed   SX     float
  Jump Speed         SY     float
  Max Speed          SM     float
  Gravity            GY     float
  Bullet Animation   B      std::string (Animation asset to use for bullets)

  ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
  Assignment Hints
  ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------

  I recommend approaching this assignment in the following order, which will
  help you debug your program along the way with minimal errors. Remember to
  do one step at a time and test wheather what you have just implemented is
  working properly before moving on to any additional steps.

  - Rendering system has already been set up for you, to help you debug:
    You can press the T key to toggle drawing textures
    You can press the C key to toggle drawing bounding boxes
    You can press the G key to toggle drawing the grid

- you can implement Animation::update() and Animation::hasEnded() at any
  time, it will not affect the gameplay mechanics whatsoever, just animation

- Implement Scene_Play::loadLevel()
  Since rendering is already completed, once you correctly read in the
  different types of entities, add them to the EntityManager and they should
  automatically be drawn to the screen. Add the correct bounding boxes
  to Tile entities, and no bounding boxes to the Dec entities. Remember
  you can toggle debug viewing of bounding boxes with the T and C keys

  As part of this step, implement Scene_Play::gridToMidPixel()
  function, which takes in as parameters a grid x,y position and an Entity,
  and returns the Vec2 position of the CENTER of that Entity. You must
  use the Animation size of that Entity to detemrine where its center point
  should be. Keep in mind that this means your Entity MUST have its
  CAnimation componenet added first, so that it can be used to calculate the
  midpoint in this function.

- Implement Scene_Play::spawnPlayer()
  Read the player configuration the the level file and spwan the player
  This is where hte player should restart when they die

- Implement some basic WASD u/l/d/r movement for the player eitity so that
  you can use this to help test collisions in the future. Remember that
  you you must use registerAction to register a new action for the scene. See
  the actions already registered for you,and the sDoAction() function for 
  syntax on how to perform actions


